const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Where is the micturition reflex center located?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Rostral pontine tegmentum","bool":true},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Disturbance in the renal reabsorption of bicarbonates in the proximal tubules leads to which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypochloremia","bool":false},{"option":"Acidic urine","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrogen retention","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"If plasma colloidal osmotic pressure is 40 mmHg, renal capillary pressure is 60 mmHg, and Bowman's capsule hydrostatic pressure is 18 mmHg, which of the following effect occurs in the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) is reduced","bool":true},{"option":"Afferent arteriolar dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of macula densa","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) is increased","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent arteriolar dilatation","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following provides arterial supply to the pelvic part of the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Gonadal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vesical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac artery","bool":true},{"option":"Renal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The examination of a cross-section of kidneys shows the renal columns of Bertin. Which statement best defines the renal columns of Bertin?","answers":[{"option":"Medullary substance that extends into cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical substance that extends into medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrons that are drained by a common collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Convoluted parts of renal tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Marks beginning of nephron","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is not the part of renal filtration barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Basal lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Continuous epithelium of glomerular capillaries","bool":true},{"option":"Fenestrated endothelium of glomerular capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Podocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"What may the kidneys enhance in response to acidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Secretion of HCO₃⁻","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of K⁺ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Urea retention","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of H⁺ ions","bool":true},{"option":"Secretion of Na⁺ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Allopurinol is a structural analog of which of the following compounds?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Inosine monophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the osmolarity of the glomerular filtrate that enters the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"400 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"100 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"200 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"300 mOsm/L","bool":true},{"option":"1200 mOsm/L","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Increased secretion of aldosterone leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A female comes into the clinic with oral ulcers, hematuria, and +1 proteinuria. 1-2 white blood cells/HPF are found on urinalysis. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Acid excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the narrowest part of the ureter, well above the urinary bladder, where stones can get lodged?","answers":[{"option":"Bladder wall","bool":false},{"option":"Major calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvicalyceal junction","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic brim","bool":true},{"option":"Minor calyx","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the correct order of the coverings of the kidneys from outwards to inwards?","answers":[{"option":"Renal fascia - Perinephric fat - Paranephric fat - Renal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Renal capsule - Renal fascia - Perinephric fat - Paranephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Perinephric fat - Renal fascia - Paranephric fat - Renal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Renal capsule - Paranephric fat - Perinephric fat - Renal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Paranephric fat - Renal fascia - Perinephric fat - Renal capsule","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following arteries is responsible for the arterial supply to the proximal part of the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Common iliac","bool":false},{"option":"Renal","bool":true},{"option":"Gonadal","bool":false},{"option":"Suprarenal","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 6-year-old female is brought to the urology clinic with the complaint of urinary incontinence. Further investigation revealed that the urine was not coming from the bladder, but was continuously dribbling from the vagina. What is the most appropriate diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Supernumerary kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic ureter","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Microscopically the Bowman's capsule comprises an inner visceral layer and an outer parietal layer. Cells lining the visceral layer have a star-shaped body with primary and secondary processes. Which of the following cells best fits this description?","answers":[{"option":"Mesangial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Brush cells","bool":false},{"option":"Podocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Simple cuboidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which part of the urogenital sinus gives rise to the urethra in females?","answers":[{"option":"Widest part of the urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Phallic part of the urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic part of the urogenital sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Vesical part of the urogenital sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"In a healthy individual, what percentage of renal plasma flow would you expect to be passed into the glomerular capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Between 75 and 80%","bool":false},{"option":"Greater than 90%","bool":false},{"option":"Between 15 and 20%","bool":true},{"option":"Between 45 and 50%","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 5%","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following structures is most involved in concentrating the urine?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial nephrons","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Juxtamedullary nephron","bool":true},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which type of transport is exhibited by the Na-K-2Cl transporter in the apical membrane of the thick ascending loop of Henle?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Counter transport","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":true},{"option":"Passive transport","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the tonicity of urine as it enters the renal collecting duct?","answers":[{"option":"Hypotonic or isotonic, but never hypertonic","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotonic","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertonic or isotonic, but never hypotonic","bool":false},{"option":"Isotonic","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertonic","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"All of the glucose is absorbed by the proximal convoluted tubule. Approximately 90% is in the first part of the proximal convoluted tubule. Which of the following transporters is responsible for transporting the major amount of glucose from the tubular lumen into the cell?","answers":[{"option":"SGLT 2","bool":true},{"option":"GLUT 2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT 4","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT 1","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT 1","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A substance \"X\" has the following properties:\r\nUrinary concentration (U) = 0 mg/ml Plasma concentration (P) = 13.6 mg/ml.\r\nIf a patient has a urinary flow rate (V) of 2 ml/min, what is the renal clearance rate of X?","answers":[{"option":"13.6 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"2 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"1 ml/min","bool":false},{"option":"0 ml/min","bool":true},{"option":"0.5 ml/min","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"If a patient has a glomerular filtration rate of 100 ml/min and is known to be clearing a therapeutic drug at a rate of 150 ml/min, what is the most appropriate comment regarding the renal processing of this drug?","answers":[{"option":"Tm of drug has been exceeded, causing clearance to rise above GFR","bool":false},{"option":"Overall processing of this drug is similar to amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Since the clearance is greater than GFR, the drug must be secreted","bool":true},{"option":"Since the clearance is greater than GFR, the drug must be reabsorbed","bool":false},{"option":"No evaluation can be made without further information","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A one-year-old boy presents to the emergency with a complaint of weakness and growth retardation. He is lethargic and anemic. Blood analysis reveals megaloblastic anemia and urinalysis shows orotic aciduria. Which of the following compounds is most likely to alleviate his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Adenine","bool":false},{"option":"Guanine","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Thymidine","bool":false},{"option":"Uridine","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A one-year-old boy was admitted to the hospital with complaints of diarrhea and vomiting. On examination, he is lethargic, and weak and on pinching the abdominal skin it goes back very slowly. Which IV fluid should be given to rehydrate the child?","answers":[{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":true},{"option":"Normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertonic saline","bool":false},{"option":"Haemacel","bool":false},{"option":"5% dextrose solution","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presents with confusion and has a sodium level of 123 mEq/l. He is diagnosed with syndrome of inappropriate antidiuretic hormone secretion (SIADH). Which type of hyponatremia is this?","answers":[{"option":"Antivolemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudovolemic","bool":false},{"option":"Hypovolemic","bool":false},{"option":"Hypervolemic","bool":false},{"option":"Euvolemic","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following organisms is the most common cause of community-acquired urinary tract infections?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia Coli","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus faecalis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is least frequently associated with focal segmental glomerulosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"IgM deposition on immunofluorescence","bool":false},{"option":"Some glomeruli are sclerosed","bool":false},{"option":"IgA deposition on immunofluorescence","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Some glomeruli are normal","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Anti-glomerular basement membrane antibody-induced glomerulonephritis accounts for less than 5% cases of human glomerulonephritis. Which of the following is the most appropriate example of this nephropathy?","answers":[{"option":"Mesangioproliferative nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Proliferation nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Crescentic nephropathy","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is least likely to be seen in nephrotic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Hematuria","bool":true},{"option":"Heavy proteinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Selective proteinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased plasma colloid osmotic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoalbuminemia","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is least likely to be correct about xanthogranulomatous pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Grossly resembles renal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Rare form of chronic pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Associated with polyomavirus infection","bool":true},{"option":"Accumulation of foamy macrophages with plasma cells, lymphocytes and giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Shows large yellow nodules","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following statements is most appropriate regarding renal transplantation?","answers":[{"option":"ABO compatibility between donor and recipient is essential","bool":true},{"option":"Immunosuppressant drugs are prescribed to selected transplant patients","bool":false},{"option":"HLA compatibility for minor antigens is not required","bool":false},{"option":"Allergen test is performed on potential recipient","bool":false},{"option":"HLA compatibility is sometimes not required","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A researcher is conducting a research study to find the prevalence of diabetes mellitus in Karachi city. Which of the following epidemiological study design is the most appropriate for this research?","answers":[{"option":"Cohort study","bool":false},{"option":"Case-control study","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":true},{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Experimental study","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"During your posting in the behavioral sciences department, you were taught about informational care and how sharing the patient's personal information is sometimes important for the patient's care. Which of the following individuals is \"authorized\" to know the patient's personal information?","answers":[{"option":"A colleague of the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Another worker from the care team providing support to the individual","bool":true},{"option":"A senior worker not involved in supporting the individual","bool":false},{"option":"A family member of the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Another health worker from another team providing care to another individual","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with complaints of diarrhea and vomiting for one day. He is semi-conscious and severely dehydrated. What is the first-line management in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"IV antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"IV fluid replacement","bool":true},{"option":"Oral antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"KYB diet","bool":false},{"option":"Oral fluid replacement","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"In a patient with severe dehydration, which organ/s become/s non-functional almost immediately?","answers":[{"option":"Eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is a cause of pre-renal acute kidney failure?","answers":[{"option":"Prostrate hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Profuse diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Acute glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 65-year-old female with chronic kidney disease secondary to hypertension has low erythropoietin levels. Which of the following conditions is the patient at risk of developing?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypomagnesemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypophosphatemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the investigation of choice to diagnose vesicoureteric reflux in a male toddler?","answers":[{"option":"IV urography","bool":false},{"option":"CT urography","bool":false},{"option":"MR urethrography","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound bladder with pre and post void volumes","bool":false},{"option":"Micturating cystourethrography","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following vessels gives rise to the renal arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Lobar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Common iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following structures enters the kidney at the hilum and brings blood to the kidneys?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Renal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Renal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following are direct branches of the renal arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Afferent arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Lobular arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate arteries","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which part of the renal tubule is impermeable to water, while solutes can pass out passively into medullary interstitial space?","answers":[{"option":"Thin ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Thick ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"In which segment of the renal tubule are the sodium-hydrogen antiporters that are involved in hydrogen ion secretion located?","answers":[{"option":"Loop of Henle - thin segment","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle - thick segment","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 46-year-old male presents to the emergency room with severe right toe pain. On examination, he had a temperature of 100.8° F, and he was moderately distressed about the pain in his toe. The right big toe was swollen, warm, red, and exquisitely tender. Synovial joint fluid was obtained and revealed rod or needle-shaped crystals. Which enzyme(s) is/are deficient in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyl transferase","bool":true},{"option":"Alkaline phosphatase, Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyl transferase, Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine deaminase, Hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyl transferase","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following best describes the urine of diabetic patients?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased volume, increased specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased volume, increased specific gravity","bool":true},{"option":"Increased volume, decreased specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Normal volume, increased specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Normal volume, decreased specific gravity","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following serves as a cofactor in de novo purine synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Folate","bool":true},{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Biotin","bool":false},{"option":"Flavin","bool":false},{"option":"Caltrate","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 60-year-old male with a history of diabetes and chronic kidney failure presents to the clinic with complaints of dyspnea, cough, malaise, and fever for 15 days. How can the glomerular filtration rate be determined in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Serum pyruvate dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"IV pyelogram","bool":false},{"option":"Renal scan","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine clearance","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 55-year-old male with COPD presents to the clinic with increased severity of shortness of breath. His immediate arterial blood gases show respiratory acidosis. What is the first step in the interpretation of arterial blood gases?","answers":[{"option":"PaCO₂","bool":false},{"option":"Anion gap","bool":false},{"option":"HCO₃ level","bool":false},{"option":"pH of blood","bool":true},{"option":"Delta-delta gap","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 40-year-old female with a history of breast carcinoma was brought to the critical care unit with the complication of metastasis. They were counseled about minimal chances of survival. The family was not convinced by your opinion and wished to consult a second specialist. What is the responsibility of the doctor in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Offer psychoeducation","bool":false},{"option":"Offer palliative care","bool":false},{"option":"Support the decision of second opinion","bool":true},{"option":"Discharge the patient immediately","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitate by counseling","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"What percentage of the total body weight does the extra-cellular fluid (ECF) account for?","answers":[{"option":"15%","bool":false},{"option":"10%","bool":false},{"option":"70%","bool":false},{"option":"5%","bool":false},{"option":"20%","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The renal sinus is a space within the kidney containing all the structures responsible for draining urine into the ureter. Which of the following structures is present in this space?","answers":[{"option":"Major calyx","bool":true},{"option":"Renal pyramids","bool":false},{"option":"Renal medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical columns","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary rays","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most common site for an ectopic kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Upper abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Perineum","bool":false},{"option":"Inguinal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Lower abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvis","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following results in an uninhibited neurogenic bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic nerve injury","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Partial injury of spinal cord or brainstem","bool":true},{"option":"Tabes dorsalis","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord injury above sacral region","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following hormones or autocoids can increase the glomerular filtration rate (GFR) by decreasing vascular resistance in the glomerular capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelial derived nitric oxide","bool":true},{"option":"Angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin I","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 5-year-old boy presents to the outpatient clinic with generalized edema and periorbital edema. Blood tests and urine analysis reveal hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.7 g proteinuria. A renal biopsy is performed. Which of the following electron microscopic features is most likely to be present in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Subendothelial deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent shaped glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Effacement of foot process but no deposits","bool":true},{"option":"Thick glomerular basement membrane with immune complex deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Subepithelial deposits","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The parents of an 11-year-old mentally impaired male child visit a local clinic. The father tells the doctor that he has 7 other children to support and someone suggested that he could sell the kidney of his mentally impaired son. What is the correct legal implication in this case according to the \"Transplantation of Human Organs and Tissues Act 2010\"?","answers":[{"option":"It is illegal to sell a kidney and should not be done","bool":true},{"option":"It is legal because patient is mentally impaired","bool":false},{"option":"It can only be donated to a relative","bool":false},{"option":"It can be sold since parents provide their consent","bool":false},{"option":"Consent of patient is needed","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The enzyme carbonic anhydrase catalyzes the formation of which of the following compounds?","answers":[{"option":"H₃PO₄","bool":false},{"option":"H₂CO₃","bool":true},{"option":"H₂PO₄","bool":false},{"option":"H₂SO₄","bool":false},{"option":"HNO₃","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The Na-K-2Cl cotransporters are present in which of the following parts of a nephron?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Thick ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Thin descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The synthesis of deoxyribonucleotides from ribonucleotides requires the enzyme ribonucleotide reductase. Which of the following is a cofactor for this enzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Thioredoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Folate","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most common route of spread of acute pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Direct spread from nearby viscera","bool":false},{"option":"From peritoneal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending spread from urethra and bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Hematogenous spread","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphogenous spread","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"In the process of pyrimidine metabolism, the deamination of cytosine produces which of the following compounds?","answers":[{"option":"Uracil","bool":true},{"option":"Thiouracil","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Adenylic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A doctor is performing a nephrostomy. Which of the following regions of the body is most appropriate to approach the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior abdominal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior abdominal wall","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior part of pelvic cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Superior part of the pelvic cavity","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Mycophenolic acid is used as an immunosuppressant drug to prevent graft rejection after transplant. Which of the following enzymes is inhibited by this drug?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate (PRPP) synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine deaminase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenylosuccinate synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Inosine monophosphate (IMP) dehydrogenase","bool":true},{"option":"Dihydrofolate reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following factors help distinguish that hematuria is of renal origin and not from the bladder?","answers":[{"option":"RBC casts","bool":true},{"option":"Hemoglobinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Sterile pyuria","bool":false},{"option":"WBC casts","bool":false},{"option":"Gross hematuria","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Under the action of which of the following hormones is potassium secreted from the principal cells of the late distal tubules and collecting ducts?","answers":[{"option":"Angiotensin I","bool":false},{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Antidiuretic hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following ions is secreted by the principal cells when stimulated by aldosterone?","answers":[{"option":"H⁺","bool":false},{"option":"Na⁺","bool":false},{"option":"Cl⁻","bool":false},{"option":"Ca⁺","bool":false},{"option":"K⁺","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the sensory innervation to the bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Sacral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Pudendal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypogastric nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic splanchnic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most commonly used test to assess renal function?","answers":[{"option":"Para-aminohippuric acid clearance","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin clearance","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine clearance","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following structures is most likely to be damaged during the surgical approach of kidneys around the 11th or 12th rib?","answers":[{"option":"Lesser sac of peritoneal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pleura","bool":true},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following cells associated with the glomerular capillaries are involved in phagocytosis of macromolecules, adjusting filtration rate, mediating immune response in a glomerulus, and providing structural support?","answers":[{"option":"Podocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mesangial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Principal cells","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The decrease in sodium chloride (NaCl) concentration in the glomerular filtrate, when sensed by the macula densa is most likely to result in which of the following responses?","answers":[{"option":"Increased release of renin from juxtaglomerular cells","bool":true},{"option":"Dilation of efferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of afferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of renin release from juxtaglomerular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of mesangial cells","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"A histopathologist observes a slide of the wall of the urinary bladder with three distinct layers the mucosa, muscularis, and serosa. Which of the following parts of the bladder is under observation?","answers":[{"option":"Superior surface","bool":true},{"option":"Trigone","bool":false},{"option":"Inferolateral surface","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following conditions results in efflux of potassium ions from the cell?","answers":[{"option":"Increased Insulin level","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"β-adrenergic stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperaldosteronism","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Aspartate enters the Krebs cycle as which of the following compounds?","answers":[{"option":"α-ketoglutarate","bool":false},{"option":"Succinyl CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Fumarate","bool":false},{"option":"Oxaloacetate","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"The pain due to a ureteric calculi can extend from the loin to the groin. This area is supplied by which of the following spinal segments?","answers":[{"option":"T12 to L3","bool":false},{"option":"S1 to S3","bool":false},{"option":"T11 to L2","bool":true},{"option":"L1 and L2","bool":false},{"option":"L1 to L3","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following parts of the male urethra is lined by pseudostratified columnar epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Bulbar urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra","bool":true},{"option":"Navicular fossa","bool":false}]}]
export default arr